字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：Reginamoon kahiko 木浅薰 想名字好难
翻译：dzysteven JohnnyG   校对：油炸电风扇   木浅薰
时间轴：biu 浪影与浓子同在  纸袋P
后期：斯人愿浓子一路走好      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第十集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
杰西卡・皮尔逊上庭
Jessica Pearson in court.
我可是很久没见到了
I haven't seen that in a while.
我们接了一个"无罪计划"的案子
We took over an Innocence Project case.
他杀了我女儿
He killed my girl!
但我相信伦纳德・贝利是无辜的
But I believe that Leonard Bailey is innocent,
我会确保他得到自己本该得到的公正判决
and I'm going to make sure that he gets the fair trial that he never had.
方法就是找些瘾君子来做证人吗
By tracking down some junkie witness?
玛利亚・戈麦斯以前都没有机会说出证词
Maria Gomez never had a chance to be heard.
伦纳德・贝利不在场证明的证人死了
Leonard Bailey's alibi witness is dead.
这不代表她的证词不存在
That doesn't mean her testimony is.
你想让我给她告诉我的事作证吗
You want me to testify to what she told me?
我徒弟冒昧地起草了一份宣誓证明
My protégé took the liberty of drawing up a sword affidavit.
现在你要么签了它
You can either sign it
要么在宣誓后撒谎说这是假的
or you can lie under oath that this isn't true.
你们的意思是本案由于伦纳德・贝利的
Are you saying that this case needs to be re-opened
代理人工作不充分  应予以重审吗
based on Leonard Bailey having inadequate representation?
我们就一定会这样做
It sure as hell is our plan now.
你设计坑我
You set me up.
我保证让这件事人尽皆知
I'm gonna make sure the world knows it.
你可以告诉任何人任何事  威廉
You can tell the world anything you want, William.
但是你没有证据
But you got no proof.
总之  我劝你还是签字同意这笔交易
Either way, I suggest you sign this deal.
-你好  -是我
- Hello? - Hey, it's me.
我可以回家了
I'm coming home.
-我们做到了  -做到了
- We did it. - We did.
天哪  这是有多少人要来啊
Whoa, how many people are joining us?
我不确定你想喝哪种威士忌
Wasn't sure which Scotch you'd want,
所以我干脆全点了
so I went ahead and ordered them all.
那我要是想喝啤酒呢
What if I'm in the mood for a beer?
你刚出狱
You just got out of prison.
不会想喝啤酒的
You're not in the mood for a beer.
好吧  你说对了
Yeah, you're right.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
真他妈好喝
Oh, damn that tastes good.
那还不是我为你准备的最好的东西
That's not even the best thing I have for ya.
-是一份工作  -看看上面的金额
- It's an offer letter. - Take a look at the number.
这是我做初级合伙人时挣的金额
This is the same money I made as a junior partner.
因为你就是初级合伙人
Because you are a junior partner.
还是当下最好的  我们需要你
The best there is. And we need you.
我才刚出狱  我可不想再进去
I just got out of prison. I'm not trying to go back.
你不会再进去的
You're not going back,
因为你是要干着律师的活儿
because even though you'll be acting as a lawyer,
你的头衔会是"顾问"
your title's gonna be "Consultant."
听着  哈维  谢谢你的邀请  但是
Look, Harvey, I appreciate the gesture, but...
因为我  大家都离开了那家律所
everyone left that firm because of me.
我不会再这样害你了
I'm not gonna do that to you again.
-迈克...  -不  听我说
- Mike-- - No, listen to me.
你做得够多了  你不用再为我做这个
You've done enough, you don't have to do this for me.
我不是为了你  我是为了我自己
I'm not doing this for you. I'm doing it for me.
我怀念和你共事的感觉
I miss working with you.
我也很怀念
I miss working with you, too.
那就帮帮忙  考虑一下
Then do me a favor: just think about it.
假如几天之后答案还是"不"
If the answer's still "no" in a few days,
我就不会再提起这件事了
I won't bring it up again.
你从来都不在家  这就是原因
Because you're never here, that's why!
我们讨论过这个问题了  芙吉妮娅
We've been over this, Virginia.
-我尽了义务  -这就是问题  亚伦
- I do my part. - That's the problem, Alan.
你以为你的义务就只是挣钱养家
You think your part is just getting a paycheck.
挣钱养家
A paycheck?
我们家的条件比我们认识的任何一家都好
This family lives like no other family we know.
-杰西卡  亲爱的...  -怎么了
- Jessica, honey-- - What's going on?
我们只是在争论
We're just having an argument.
会没事的
It'll be okay.
你没必要在她面前遮遮掩掩  亚伦
You don't need to sugarcoat things for her, Alan.
假如你能在我们身边而不是在外面
And you'd know this if you were ever here
忙你自己的事你就会明白这一点
instead of out doing whatever it is you're doing.
我忙的是救命的事  你知道的
What I'm out doing is saving lives, and you know it.
也许你像尽心对待你的病人一样
Well, maybe if you worked as hard on our relationship
用心对待我们的关系
as you do for your patients,
就不会出现现在这种情况了
what's happening wouldn't be happening.
现在什么情况
What's happening?
你父亲和我要分开一段时间
Your father and I are taking a little break for a while.
多久
How long?
我不知道  宝贝
I don't know, baby.
我不知道
I don't know.
哈维
Harvey?
我很乐意闲聊  但我一小时后要上庭
I'd love to chit chat, but I've got trial in an hour,
所以不是什么要紧的事的话...
so unless it's urgent...
我只是想谢谢你
I just wanted to thank you.
为迈克的事
For Mike.
你不用为了这事谢我
You don't have to thank me for that.
我和你一样想要他出来
I wanted him out as much as you did.
我知道  但萨特的问题上你不必挺我的
I know, but you didn't have to back me when it came to Sutter,
而你挺了我
and you did.
你也会为我做同样的事情的
You would've done the same for me.
如今他出来了
And now that he is out,
我们就好好工作  把律所维护下去吧
let's get back to the business of keeping this firm alive.
如果是我  首先我会保住吉姆・雷诺兹
If I were you, I would start by locking up Jim Reynolds.
-什么  -你在说什么
- Excuse me? - What're you talking about?
我在说你们的第一个客户
I'm talking about the fact that your first client
正在背着你们偷偷想投奔别家
is shopping for another attorney behind your back.
别告诉我你准备出手了
Don't tell me, you're about to pounce.
我没想挖你们的墙脚  哈维
I'm not trying to poach your client, Harvey.
但如果你们留不住他  我就不客气了
But if you can't keep him, I will.
我很感谢你为此前来  罗伯特
I appreciate you coming down here, Robert,
但给对手通风报信这种事
but it's not exactly your style
可不是你的风格啊
to give the competition a heads-up.
我小时候
When I was kid,
洋基队和红袜队是有史以来最棒的对手
the Yankees and the Red Sox were the best damn rivalry ever.
你想说什么
What's your point?
我想说的是
My point is,
自从巴基・登特在78年
after Bucky Dent hit that
打出了那个完美的全垒打
beautiful home run in '78,
红袜队就没落了
the Sox fell off a cliff.
此后再也没什么乐趣了
It wasn't any fun anymore.
你是说你不想称霸这个领域吗
You're saying you don't want to dominate the division?
我是说你们没落了
I'm saying you fell off a cliff.
如果你们想有机会重返赛场...
And if you want a chance to get back in the game...
我们最好留住吉姆・雷诺兹
We better keep Jim Reynolds.
而且最好立刻行动
And you better get on it right now.
因为我可能不会挖你们墙脚
Because I may not be looking to pounce,
但市里其他的律所会
but every firm in this city is.
该死的
Damn it.
现在最不需要的就是吉姆・雷诺兹的离开
The last thing we need is Jim Reynolds leaving right now.
为什么不打电话呢  就像上次那样
What happened to calling, like he did last time,
而要背着我们行动
instead of going behind our backs?
我告诉你为什么
I'll tell you what happened.
他就像他说的那样被董事会施压了
He's getting pressure from his board like he said he would.
而你说我们会在月底之前回归正轨
And you said we'd get back on our feet by the end of the month
我们确实做到了
and we did.
你就是要去告诉他们这一点
And that's exactly what you're gonna tell them.
为什么是我去
What do you mean me?
你是没听到我五分钟前和你说的话吗
Did you not hear what I just told you five minutes ago?
-我一小时后要上庭  -我不管
- I've got trial in an hour. - I don't care.
一开始你就是他的首席律师
You've been his lead attorney since they got here.
如果你不亲自去  我们就要失去他了
If you don't go over yourself, we're gonna lose him.
-那你带路易去  -杰西卡
- Then take Louis with you. - Jessica--
哈维  你只要跟他们开诚布公
Harvey, all you have to do is open up our books
展现出我们实力依旧就行了
and show them we're standing on solid ground.
或者你可以先处理这件事  庭审申请延期
Or you can make this the priority and get a continuance.
这是个死刑的上诉案  哈维
It's a death row appeal, Harvey.
如果我一开庭就说我的公司比人命还重要
How's it gonna look if I start a trial saying that my business
别人会怎么看
is more important than a man's life?
你可以不这么说
You don't say that.
就说有其他的原因
You come up with some other reason.
不管我找什么理由
Whatever reason I come up with,
检察官都会说我不在乎人命
that prosecutor's gonna make it look like I don't care.
我不会冒这个险的
And I'm not taking that risk.
-杰西卡  -行了  别说了
- Jessica-- - No, enough.
如果你想谢我在迈克的事上挺了你一把
You want to thank me for having your back with Mike,
那就搞定这件事
then take care of this.
唐娜  格蕾琴在哪
Donna, where the hell is Gretchen?
-我不知道  -你给我把她找来
- I have no idea. - Well, you need to find her.
哈维  怎么了  你找她干什么
Harvey, what's going on? What do you need her for?
我不是找她  我是要找路易
I don't need her, I need Louis,
我不知道他去哪了
and I don't know where he is.
你干吗不早说
Well, why didn't you start with that?
他和客户有个紧急会议  他赶去开会了
He had an emergency meeting with a client and he ran out of here.
-什么时候  -半小时前
- When? - Half an hour ago.
他离开前我看到他进电梯了
I saw him at the elevators before he left.
他一回来你马上告诉他
You tell him the second he gets back
我有事情要跟他谈
I need to talk to him.
哈维  什么事
Harvey, what's going on?
吉姆・雷诺兹威胁我们说要解约
Jim Reynolds is threatening to leave.
什么
What?
哈维  他警告杰西卡的那晚我也在
Harvey, I was there the night he put Jessica on notice.
如果他要离开  那你可没时间等路易
If he's leaving, then you don't have time to wait for Louis.
我知道  但如果我搞不定雷诺兹
I know, but if I can't make it work with Reynolds,
我一回来就需要路易帮忙
I'm gonna need Louis the second I get back.
我这就去
I'm on it.
这是什么玩意
What the hell is this?
你知道这是什么  传票
You know what that is. It's a subpoena.
我签了宣誓书  你已经得到想要的了
I signed your affidavit. You have what you need.
你不会真以为你不用给贝利的
Did you really think you wouldn't have to testify
不在场证明作证吧
that Bailey had an alibi?
我只是没想到你会把我
What I didn't think was that you were going to
定义成不称职
paint me as incompetent.
我们做了12年前你本该做的事
We did what you should've done 12 years ago.
代表好自己的委托人
Represent your client.
我经手这件案子的时候
And you weren't even forming sentences
你还不会说话呢
when I handled this case.
但我现在会说了  所以你不用生气
Well, I'm forming sentences now, so instead of being angry,
你应该谢谢我们没有代表伦纳德
you should be thanking us for not bringing an action
起诉你
against you on Leonard's behalf.
-放马过来  -乔治娜  你犯了错误
- Bring it on. - Georgina, you made a mistake.
不管你是否愿意
We're giving you the chance to fix it
我们是在给你机会改正它
whether you like it or not.
我才不在乎你在做什么
I don't give a shit what you think you're doing.
我不是来改正错误的
I'm not here to fix it.
我来这里是因为这个
I'm here because of this.
那我们法庭见了
Then I'll see you on the stand.
哈维  你怎么来了
Harvey, what're you doing here?
我是来阻止你食言的
I'm here to stop you from breaking your word.
那我建议
Then I suggest you turn around
你还是向后转赶紧离开这里
and walk out of here as fast as you can.
你先听我说
Look, just hear me out.
你跟杰西卡谈的那晚
The night you spoke to Jessica,
我们是损失了75%的收入来源
we'd lost 75% of our revenue stream.
-但从那天起  -你听我说
- But since then-- - Listen to me.
我的董事会和你们的收入没有关系
My taking meetings has nothing to do with your revenue stream.
那到底是为了什么
Then what the hell's this about?
是关于你故意搞砸了
It's about the rumors that you tanked
威廉・萨特的案子
William Sutter's case.
-我什么都没干  -我也是这么说的
- I didn't tank shit. - I told him that.
我一个字都不相信
I don't believe any of it.
你信不信不重要  吉姆
Well, it doesn't matter what you believe, Jim.
董事会信就够了
Because the board believes it.
让我猜猜看  你是董事会成员
And let me guess, you're the board.
唐纳德・曼尼斯
Donald Mannis.
我可以和你握手  但我不想让你
I'd shake your hand, but I wouldn't want your
阴险的职业道德玷污了我
shady ethics rubbing off on me.
唯一能玷污你的东西  唐纳德
The only thing that's rubbing off on you, Donald,
就是威廉・萨特的一堆屁话
is a load of bullshit from William Sutter.
你的前任助理曾和是他女婿在监狱的室友
Your former associate was in prison with his son-in-law,
萨特倒闭的那天正是你伙计出狱的那天
and the day Sutter goes down, your guy gets out.
你可以说这都是扯淡的
You may call that bullshit,
但我觉得这事听起来合情合理
but his story adds up to me.
我们公司不能有一个
And this company can't have an attorney
会出卖自己客户的律师
who's willing to turn on his own client.
知道我的难处了吗
You see what I'm dealing with?
我开董事会只是
I only took those meetings because I'm being pressured
迫于压力
to take those meetings.
我懂了  这个混蛋要篡你的位
I get it. That asshole wants your job.
他不只是想
He doesn't just want it.
如果我不让你走  他可就要得逞了
If I don't let you go, he's gonna get it.
唯一可能改变局面的就是让杰西卡进来
And the one thing that might've changed that was Jessica
向他展示一下我们对她的重要性
coming in here and showing him how important we are to her.
你对她很重要  吉姆
You are important to her, Jim.
但杰西卡现在正在庭审
But Jessica's in trial right now.
那你应该派路易・利特来
Then you should've sent Louis Litt,
因为那个混蛋最不想看到的就是
because the last thing that asshole needed to see
看到你出现在这里
when he walked in here was you.
法官大人  请求将证人视为敌意证人
Your Honor, permission to treat the witness as hostile.
什么理由
On what grounds?
证人还一句话没说呢
The witness hasn't even said anything yet.
理由是五分钟前
On the grounds that five minutes ago,
她告诉我她宁愿不让伦纳德・贝利一案
she told me she'd sooner deny Leonard Bailey
重审也不会冒险承认自己失职
a new trial than to risk looking incompetent.
是真的吗
Is this true?
是
Yes.
批准
Then permission granted.
凯西女士  你做伦纳德・贝利的公诉人时
Ms. Casey, when you were Leonard Bailey's public defender,
他有告诉过你案发当时
did he tell you that at the time of the murders,
他在一个名叫玛利亚・戈麦斯女人的公寓里吗
he was in the apartment of a woman named Maria Gomez?
是的
Yes.
也就是说他不但有不在场证明
Which means he not only had an alibi,
还有一个能作证的证人
he had a witness that could testify to it.
-我说的对吗  -对
- Is that correct? - Yes.
那到底为什么这个证人从来没有出庭
Then why in God's name didn't that witness ever take the stand?
因为她在庭审开始前
Because she left town without telling anyone
没通知任何人就离开了
right before the trial started.
-你找过她吗  -我找过
- Did you try to locate her? - Yes, I did.
-你有多努力找她  -尽我所能
- How hard did you look? - I did my best.
事实是  你根本就没有找她  对不对
The truth is, you didn't look for her at all, did you?
并非如此
That's not true.
我尽了所有努力去找她了
I did everything I could to try to find her.
但你并没有找到
But you didn't.
如果你找到了
And if you had,
那就应该有一个不在场证人
there would have been an alibi witness
向陪审团证明他根本
that would've told the jury that he couldn't have possibly
没有作案的可能
have committed those murders.
那个证人是个有前科的瘾君子
That witness was a drug addict with a prior conviction,
就算上庭会作证也会被检方驳斥到死
and she would have been eviscerated on the stand.
所以你又何必去找她呢
Then why did you try to find her at all?
我来设想一下吧
Let me suggest an answer.
你去找了她  因为你知道如果你找了
You did try to find her, because you knew if you did,
伦纳德・贝利就会被判无罪
Leonard Bailey would be found innocent.
但你没有做到
But you dropped the ball.
伦纳德・贝利成了死囚
Leonard Bailey went to death row.
而你宁愿他不被平反
And you'd rather let him stay there
也不愿承认事实
than to admit the truth.
凯西小姐  在你眼里
Ms. Casey, in your estimation,
伦纳德・贝利是无辜的吗
was Leonard Bailey innocent?
反对  法官大人  这是提出结论
Objection, Your Honor, calls for a conclusion.
法官大人
Your Honor,
她们让她作证就是为了证明他是否无辜
they opened the door to this when they put her on the stand,
没有人比他自己的律师更有资格做结论
and no one is more qualified to answer than his own attorney.
我允许了  凯西小姐请回答
I'll allow it. Ms. Casey?
我当时认为伦纳德・贝利是有罪的
I thought Leonard Bailey was guilty.
现在也这么认为
And I still do.
路易  下次你有什么紧急会议
Louis, the next time you have an emergency meeting,
给我提前说一声
you better clear it with me.
我会记住的  哈维
I'll keep that in mind for the future, Harvey.
但我有紧急会议就是因为你
But the reason I had an emergency meeting was you.
你说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
詹森交易团听说你故意打输萨特的案子
Jensen Analytics heard a rumor you tanked Sutter's case
威胁说要解约
and they're threatening to walk.
该死  你怎么说的
Shit. What'd you tell them?
你觉得我还能怎么说
What do you think I told them?
我说威廉・萨特是个满口谎话的混蛋
I told them William Sutter's a lying son of a bitch
为达目的不择手段口不择言
who'll do or say anything to get what he wants.
他们怎么说
What did they say?
他们说如果杰西卡最老的委托人都离开
They said if Jessica's oldest client's leaving,
他们又有什么理由留下
why should they stay?
该死
Goddamn it.
哈维  如果他们这么想了  那我们
Harvey, if they think that, then it's just a matter of time
其他委托人会这么想也只是时间问题
until all our clients think that.
也就是说我们必须保住吉姆・雷诺兹
Which means we need to get Jim Reynolds to stay.
怎么跟杰西卡说
What're we gonna tell Jessica?
我们跟她说如果她再不处理雷诺兹的事
We're gonna tell her if she doesn't do something
她很快也就没有一个公司
about Reynolds soon, she's not gonna have a firm
可以回了
to come back to.
瑞秋  听着  这已经是最好的结果了
Rachel, listen to me, it went as well as it could've.
你不用这么忧虑
You don't have to look so worried.
我怎么可能不忧虑
How can I not look worried?
迈克  那个女人直接说认为他有罪
Mike, that woman said that she thought he was guilty
而且这句话还成了检方证据
and the prosecutor got it on record.
杰西卡在这之前就证明了
And Jessica got it on record that she was incompetent
她的失职
before he did that.
陪审团知道的
The jury heard it.
是啊  但是你也看到了陪审团的样子
Yeah, but you saw the jury as well as I did.
他们并不信
They're not convinced.
让伦纳德作证
Put Leonard on the stand.
迈克  我们还没教他对答呢
Mike, we haven't prepped him yet.
-他还没准备  -瑞秋  听我说
- He's not ready. - Rachel, just listen to me.
我上庭时
When I was on trial,
不仅是给了陪审团一个释放我的理由
I didn't just give the jury a reason to let me go.
而是给了他们一个想释放你的理由
You gave them a reason to want to let you go.
没错  而且他们也如我所愿了
Exactly, and it turns out, they were going to.
而且我还是有罪的
And I was guilty.
那你觉得他们面对一个本身就无罪的人
What do you think they're gonna do for a man
会怎么做呢
who's actually innocent?
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我需要见你
I needed to see you.
我也是
Me too.
今天过得真糟
Had a rough day.
还得到了坏消息
Got some bad news.
见到你真是让人心情好转
You're a sight for sore eyes.
路易
Louis...
怎么了
What's wrong?
我今天去看了医生
I had a doctor's appointment this morning.
不管什么病  我们都共同面对
Well, whatever it is, we can deal with it together.
现代医学很厉害的
Modern medicine is a wonder.
-基本没有无法治愈的  -我怀孕了
- There's almost nothing that they can't-- - I'm pregnant.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我虽然知道自己很厉害
I mean, I knew the Litt sperm were powerful,
-但是这也太快了  -路易
- but this has to be some kind of record. - Louis.
不会吧
Don't tell me.
-是他的  -路易  我真的很抱歉
- It's his. - Louis, I'm so sorry.
我并不想这样的
I didn't mean for this to happen.
-我一向很谨慎  -我不在乎
- I'm usually so careful. - I don't care.
路易  我觉得你不知道自己在说什么
Louis, I don't think you know what you're saying.
不  我很清楚自己在说什么
No, I know exactly what I'm saying.
我爱你
I love you.
如果跟你在一起意味着要养别人的孩子
And if being with you means raising another man's child,
那我就养个别人的孩子
then I'll raise another man's child.
你现在是这么说了  但你会后悔的
You say that now, but it hasn't sunk in yet.
不会的
That's not true.
我明天也会这么说
I'm gonna say the same thing tomorrow
后天大后天还会这么说
and the day after that and the day after that.
到了那时候你再说吧
Then say it to me then.
但今天我们都很累了
But it has been a long day for both of us,
我想我们都需要休息
and I think we should both just get some sleep.
塔拉  跟我回家吧
Tara, please come home with me.
晚安  路易
Good night, Louis.
杰西卡  我们有麻烦了
Jessica, we have a problem.
马上要下班我可不想听到这句话  哈维
Not what I want to hear on my way out, Harvey.
那你肯定不想知道你必须出席
Then you're not gonna want to hear that you need to be at
吉姆・雷诺兹的下场董事会
Jim Reynolds' next board meeting.
听起来你好像没解决问题
That doesn't sound like you put out the fire.
我没解决的是关于我们故意损害
What I couldn't put out were the rumors
萨特的案子以交换迈克的流言
that we threw Sutter's case to get Mike out.
逗我呢吗  原来是因为这个
Are you kidding me? That's what this is about?
杰西卡  不是吉姆想解约
Jessica, it's not Jim.
他很忠诚  一直如此
He's loyal and always has been.
我猜猜  是唐纳德・曼尼斯
Don't tell me. It's Donald Mannis
利用此事挤兑对手
using this shit as a power play.
没错  而且我直接中招了
Exactly. And I walked right into it,
因为你没有跟我一起去
because I showed up without you.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
杰西卡  现在我们只能保住雷诺兹
Jessica, the only thing we can do is hold onto Reynolds
然后祈祷其他人不解约
and hope the others fall in line.
好吧  安排周二的会议
All right, set up a meeting for Tuesday morning.
那时候案子应该会结了
The trial should be over by then.
但是哈维  如果萨特继续这样散播谣言
But Harvey, it won't make a bit of difference
说我们是故意损害案子的律师
if Sutter's out there telling the world
那开会也不会有多大改变的
we're the kind of lawyers that throw cases.
不管怎么做  你想办法让他闭嘴
You do what you have to-- you shut that man the hell up.
他是谁
Who's he?
伦纳德  这是我未婚夫  迈克
Leonard, this is my fiancé, Mike.
他曾在我们公司工作  现在他有个主意
He used to work at the firm and he has an idea.
让伦纳德说出自己的故事
Let Leonard tell his story.
太冒险
That's risky.
我们这是在给他们机会把他粉饰成
We're giving them the chance to paint him
一位瘾君子和罪犯
as a drug user and a criminal.
他们已经在这么做了
They're already doing that.
而且他们不会就此停止
And they're not gonna stop.
伦纳德  你和我们有同样的决定权
Leonard, this is as much your call as it is ours.
你希望怎么做
What do you want to do?
我上次就想说出自己的心里话
I wanted to say my piece last time,
但那位女士不让我说  所以拜托了
but that lady didn't let me, so please,
让我出庭  给我个说出来的机会吧
put me on that stand and give me a chance to say it now.
好的
Okay.
辩方准备好传唤下一位证人了吗
Is the defense ready to call their next witness?
辩方传唤伦纳德・贝利作证  法官大人
The defense calls Leonard Bailey, Your Honor.
我们同时请求准许赞恩小姐
We'd also like to request that Ms. Zane
对证人进行提问
be permitted to question the witness.
反对  赞恩小姐是位法学院的学生
Objection, Ms. Zane is a law student,
并不是律师协会的一员
not an admitted member of the bar.
她同时也当了八年的
She's also been a practicing paralegal
法律助理
for the last eight years.
就算她是美国总统我也不在乎
I don't care if she was the President of the United States.
她并不是一位律师
She's not a lawyer
而且他们这是在设法促成无效审判
and they're laying grounds for a mistrial.
法官大人  贝利先生的第一位律师
Your Honor, it's obvious Mr. Bailey's first attorney
显然并不在乎他的死活
didn't care about him at all.
但赞恩小姐苦苦争取到了这个案子的重审
But Ms. Zane fought to have this case taken on,
如果不是她我们今天甚至都不会在这里
and she's the reason we're even here today.
正因如此  贝利先生仅仅希望
Which is why Mr. Bailey is simply asking
现在可以由她来为他进行辩护
that she be with him now.
所以除非检方对自己太缺乏自信
So unless the prosecution is so unsure of its case
以至于都搞不定一位法学院学生
that he can't handle a law student,
我们请求准许她对证人进行提问
we ask that she be allowed to question the witness.
检方撤回反对
Prosecution withdraws its objection.
那么你的请求被允许了
Then your request is granted.
哈维
Harvey.
我就觉得你或许会来拜访我
I thought I might get a visit from you.
我不是跟你说过叫你不要多嘴了吗
And I thought I told you to keep your mouth shut.
你出卖我之时我就不再听从你的意见了
Well, I stopped taking advice from you when you sold me out.
在我报警前  立刻从我的地盘上滚出去
Now get the hell off my property before I call the police.
不过这有个问题  威廉
There's only one problem with that, William.
这里不再是你的地盘了
This isn't your property anymore.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
明早8点
At 8:00 A.M. tomorrow morning,
这处房产就将被政府收走了
it's being seized by the government.
放屁
Bullshit.
这里是宅地状态
This is a homestead state.
实际上呢  我做了些调查
Turns out, I did a little checking,
在你卖掉上一处房产前你就买下了这里
and you closed on this house before you sold the last one,
也就意味着他们能  也会收走这处房产
which means they can take it and they're going to.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
你得恢复我的声誉
You're gonna repair my reputation.
而你的第一步是
And you're gonna start by
给吉姆・雷诺兹的每一位董事会成员
calling every member of Jim Reynolds' board
打电话告知他们  你之所以造谣我
and telling them that you spread those rumors about me
是因为你是个满嘴谎言的混蛋
because you're a lying son of a bitch.
你为什么觉得他们会相信我
And what makes you think they'll believe me?
因为当你有动力的时候  威廉
Because you're a hell of a salesman, William,
你可是个超棒的销售
when you're motivated,
而我相当确定当你刑满出狱
and I'm pretty sure that when you get out of prison,
你会非常有动力不让自己露宿街头的
you're gonna be motivated not to live on the street.
我当时和我朋友玛利亚嗑药嗑嗨了
I was getting high with my friend Maria.
我并不否认
I won't deny that.
但我对那些孩子们  只有帮助的心
But all I did to those kids was try and help them.
帮他们什么
Help them how?
当时我和玛利亚饿了  所以出去找吃的
Me and Maria got hungry so we went to get something to eat.
就在那个时候我们看到了他们
That's when we saw them.
躺在人行道上
Lying there on the sidewalk...
全身都是血
with blood all over 'em.
玛利亚  她  她吓坏了
Maria, she, uh... she freaked out,
但我当时想都没想  所以我就跑上前去
but I wasn't thinking, so I just ran up.
我是说  他们是孩子啊  你知道吗
I mean, they were kids, you know?
他们  他们有麻烦了
They--they were in trouble.
然后发生了什么
So then what happened?
我叫玛利亚去找人来帮忙
Well, I yelled for Maria to get help.
但那个男孩
But the boy...
他已经断气了
he was already gone.
而那个女孩  一直在不停地喊救命
And the girl, she just kept asking for help,
一遍又一遍
over and over.
我留在那里陪她
I stayed with her.
然后警察就来了
And then the police came.
紧接着
And the next thing you know,
我就被控犯下了谋杀罪
I was being charged with murder.
伦纳德
Leonard...
你入狱前已经结婚了  对吗
you were married before you went to prison, weren't you?
我妻子  在我入狱两年后离开了我
My wife, she left me two years after I went away.
她说她再也忍受不了了
She said she couldn't handle it anymore.
那你的孩子们呢
And what about your children?
你还能见到他们吗
Do you still see them?
我已经十年多没见过我儿子了
I haven't seen my son in over ten years.
而直到你找到我女儿  告诉她我是无辜的
And I hadn't seen Maya until you found her
并且你会证明这一点
and told her I was innocent
我才见到了玛雅
and you were going to prove it.
她就坐在那边
That's her right there.
伦纳德  你有什么话想对她说的吗
Leonard, is there something that you would like to say to her?
我因未行之罪失去了12年的时光
I lost 12 years for a crime I didn't commit.
但如果最终我能
But I won't regret any of it
洗脱罪名并和你团聚的话
if it ends up being the thing
我对之前的一切一点都不后悔
that got me clean and reunited with you.
因为如果我
Because if I died
在你相信你父亲犯了这样的罪的情况下死去
with you believing your father did this...
她不这么想的
She doesn't think that.
她知道你没有伤害那些孩子
She knows that you didn't hurt those kids.
我没有问题了  法官大人
I have no further questions, Your Honor.
法官大人  我们保留
Your Honor, we reserve the right
盘诘被告的权利
to cross examine the defendant.
但现在  既然他声称他知道
But for now, since he's claiming he knows
作为一位悲伤的父亲是什么样的心情
what it feels like to be an aggrieved father,
我希望传唤维克托・福雷斯特出庭作证
I'd like to call Victor Forrest to the stand.
感谢你愿意作证  福雷斯特先生
Thank you for agreeing to do this, Mr. Forrest.
我知道这对于你来说一定很不容易
I know how difficult it must be for you.
你能跟我们说说你女儿吗
Would you mind telling us a little bit about your daughter?
我该怎么说呢
What can I say?
金是我们的一切  她可爱  善良
Kim was our everything-- she was sweet, kind.
很有幽默感
Incredible sense of humor.
她还踢足球  对吗
She played soccer, didn't she?
我以前常去看着她在球场上奔跑
Used to watch her run up and down the field.
乐此不疲  她就一直奔跑着
Never got tired, she just kept running,
大大的笑容写在她脸上
big smile on her face.
她的笑容是如此美丽
She had such a beautiful smile.
显然你非常爱她
It's obvious you loved her very much.
我不仅仅爱她  我试图保护她
I didn't just love her. I tried to protect her.
我警告她要小心那些男孩子
I warned her about boys.
以及毒品
Drugs.
而且我跟她说"有任何麻烦
And I said, "If you're ever in trouble,
打电话给我"
you call me."
而最让我难过的是
And the thing that gets me is,
她那晚确实打电话给我了
she did call that night.
并非因为她碰到了麻烦
Not to say she was in trouble.
而是告诉我她就要回来了
To say she was coming home.
但她最终没能回来
But she never did make it home.
是  而且我也不管那瘾君子作证要说什么
No, and I don't care what some junkie witness was gonna say.
他们发现那个畜生就站在我女儿的身边
They found that animal standing over my little girl's body.
他身上满是我女儿的鲜血
Her blood all over him.
他一夜之间夺走了我的一切
He took away my everything in one night.
而他这么做不过是为了换钱嗑更多药
And he did it for money to buy more drugs.
那你对他对陪审团说的那番话有什么感想
And how do you feel about the speech he gave to the jury?
他说希望能给他和他家人第二次机会
He talked about getting a second chance with his family.
那我的家人呢
What about my family?
我们的生活在那晚彻底崩塌
Our lives were ruined that night.
我的女儿连第一次机会都没有
My little girl never even got a first chance.
我没有问题了  法官大人
No further questions, Your Honor.
福雷斯特先生
Mr. Forrest...
你亲眼看到伦纳德・贝利杀死你女儿了吗
Did you actually see Leonard Bailey kill your daughter?
没有  但这并不代表
Of course I didn't, but that doesn't mean--
我没有问题了  法官大人
No further questions, Your Honor.
唐娜  能给我一分钟吗
Donna, can I talk to you for a second?
既然你那么诚恳
Well, since you asked so nicely,
我可以给你两分钟
I'll even give you two.
我要告诉路易一个坏消息
I have some bad news I have to give Louis,
然而我和他好不容易和好
and since he and I are finally in a good place...
你想知道怎么做才能又告诉他消息
You want to know how to break it to him
又不会再次和他闹翻
without blowing things up again.
知我莫若你
Yeah.
坏消息是有多坏
How bad is it?
很不好
It's not good.
那就和你刚刚和我说的那样说给他
Then do what you just did with me.
带着诚意去找他  开门见山直白的说
Approach him with respect, pull the Band-Aid off,
并且如果你那时的表情和现在
and if you have that same look on your face
一模一样的话
as you do right now,
他会以礼相待的
he'll send you on your way with a handshake.
感谢建议  唐纳
Thanks, Donna.
斯图
Stu?
很高兴和你们公用办公室
It was nice having you here.
怎么了
What?
你真该看看你今天吓跑肯迪克的威武样子
You should've seen yourself thunder away at Kendrick today.
你太帅啦
You were amazing.
而且如果我是道森或者唐尼的话
And if I were Dawson or Downey
而且我必须在你和你父亲之间
and I had to choose between you and your father
选择一个为我辩护的话
to represent me on this,
一周的每天我都会选你
I'd choose you any day of the week
周日更会加倍想选你
and twice on Sunday.
你到底在说啥
What're you talking about?
《义海雄风》啊
I'm talking about "A Few Good Men."
迈克  我现在没空和你扯电影梗
Mike, I don't have time for movie quotes right now.
瑞秋  我不是要和你逗趣扯电影梗
I'm not trying to quote a movie, Rachel,
我只是想告诉你无论那女生的父亲说什么
I'm trying to tell you that it doesn't matter
都不用理
what that girl's father said.
你还在这个案子里
You're still in this,
而且你在庭上的表现好赞
and you were great up there.
等下  你说她父亲
Wait a minute, her father.
他怎么了
What about him?
他说玛利亚是个瘾君子证人
He called Maria a junkie witness.
他怎么会连她嗑药的事情都知道呢
How would he even know that she was a drug user?
你在说什么呀  跟我一样啊
What do you mean? The same way I would know.
伦纳德和他的公诉人在法庭上都这么说了
Leonard and his public defender said so on the stand.
不是  当他找我说让我别再管这件事时
No, but he used those exact words when he came at me
用了一模一样的词
trying to get me to drop this whole thing.
-他找过你  -没事  我对付过去了
- He came at you? - It's fine, I handled it.
但他确实试图恐吓我来着
But he did try to intimidate me.
而一个恐吓了你的人
And a man who would intimidate you
很可能也对玛丽亚做过同样的事
might do the same thing to Maria Gomez.
是  但我觉得他没有恐吓他
Yeah, but I don't think he intimidated her.
我想他应该是做了相反的举动
I think he did the opposite.
你在说什么
What're you saying?
我是说我觉得我们去拜访一下他吧
I'm saying I think we need to pay that man a visit.
路易  有时间吗
Louis, do you have a minute?
实话实说  斯图
Tell you the truth, Stu,
我现在很忙
I kind of have a full plate right now,
所以除非事关生死
so unless it's a matter of life and death,
不然你就等等吧
I'd rather it wait.
这事不能等
This can't wait.
我们得搬走了
We have to move out.
你说的搬走是什么意思
What do you mean, "Move out"?
就是我们要搬迁办公室了
We're relocating.
我想亲自和你讲
I wanted to tell you in person
免得伤害感情
so there's no hard feelings.
扯淡  你不能搬走啊
Oh, bullshit, you can't do this.
路易  我别无选择
Louis, I don't have a choice.
萨特两天前破产了
Sutter went bankrupt two days ago,
而法律上我们公司是属于他们的
and they owed us under their contract.
他们要我们搬到他们的办公室减轻债务
They're offering us their space to cover their obligations
而明天之前我必须答应他们
and I have to say yes by tomorrow.
如果不是我们你们都不会有这义务
You wouldn't even have those obligations, Stu,
斯图
if it weren't for us.
我知道  但我不能和我的老板们说
I know that, but I can't tell my bosses
就因为你们帮了我个忙
I'm passing on a fortune in free rent
我就要拒绝免费办公室
'cause you guys did me a solid.
那你告诉他们你都签了租赁协议了
Well, then you tell them you have a lease
中途退租我就告你
and I'm gonna sue your goddamn ass.
路易  租赁协议有个条款是
Louis, there's a clause in the lease
30天内可退租  你知道的
that gives me a 30-day out and you know it.
斯图  拜托了
Stu, please.
你现在不能这么做啊
You cannot do this to us now.
-至少今晚不行  -抱歉  路易
- Not tonight. - I'm sorry, Louis.
我真的不想害你们  如果
I hate to hang you out to dry
我有别的办法帮忙  我一定会的
and if I could help you in another way, I would.
但是我们真的不能再租这个地方了
But we can't rent this space.
我们没什么好讲
I have nothing to say to you.
拜托  福勒斯特  我不想跟你说话时
Please, Mr. Forrest, you confronted me
你还是质问了我
when I didn't want to talk to you,
而且我也尊重你  听你说完了话
and I gave you the respect to hear what you had to say.
至少您也给予相同的尊重听我们把话说完
You can at least hear what we have to say.
给你们60秒  然后我就叫警察了
You got 60 seconds, then I'm calling the police.
尽管报警  当他们到的时候
Go ahead, but when they get here,
我们就告诉他们你送走了玛利亚・戈麦斯
we'll tell them all about how you sent Maria Gomez away
导致她无法作证
so that she couldn't testify.
-你们在说什么胡话  -是乱讲吗
- That's insane. - Is it?
因为一个从未被法庭记录为瘾君子的证人
Because a woman who was never in the court record as a drug user
去了她绝无可能负担得起的戒毒所
went to a rehab facility she could never afford
而你对她熟悉到1个月前
and you know enough about her
就当我面叫她吸毒者
to call her a druggie to my face a month ago.
这无法证明任何事情
That's not proof of anything.
如果你是无辜的也不会这么接我们的话
And that's not the answer of an innocent man.
福雷斯特先生
Look, Mr. Forrest,
您所承担的巨大痛苦我都无法想象
I can't begin to understand what you've been through,
但现在因为您的所做作为
but right now, the wrong man is sitting on death row
一个无辜的人成了死囚
because of what you did.
-我什么也没做  -拜托你了
- I didn't do shit. - Please.
你就不能想想伦纳德・贝利经历了什么吗
Can't you imagine what this has been like for Leonard Bailey,
他过去的12年里所遭受的吗
what his life has looked like for the past 12 years?
我唯一想去想象的
The only thing I want to imagine
就是那个男人咽下他最后一口气之后
is what my life's gonna be like
我的生活该有的样子
after that man takes his final breath.
你们的时间到了
Your time is up.
路易  你没事吧
Louis, is everything okay?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我的意思是我知道斯图的事了
I mean, I saw what happened with Stu.
我知道他要离开  但一切都会好起来的
I know he's leaving, but it's gonna be okay.
哈维会搞定吉姆・雷诺兹的事
Harvey's gonna fix things with Jim Reynolds,
我们会找到更多的客户
we're gonna get more clients--
塔拉怀孕了
Tara's pregnant.
孩子不是我的
It's not mine.
那你跟她说了什么
What did you tell her?
我告诉她我要和她在一起
I told her I'm going to stay with her
并且尽力支持她
and support her every way I can,
因为我爱她
because I'm in love with her.
她怎么说的
And what did she say?
她说我们需要先冷静一下
She said we need to sleep on it
因为我会后悔
because it hasn't sunk in for me.
那你为什么这么沮丧呢
Then what were you so upset about?
要是她说这些话
What if she's saying that
是因为她不知道该做什么那怎么办呢
because she can't decided what she's gonna do?
-路易  -我怎么知道她不会一早起来
- Louis-- - How do I know she didn't wake up this morning
就决定回去找他呢
and decide to run back to him?
事情不是这样的
That's not what's going on.
这是一个重大决定
This is a huge decision
她想要确定
and she wants to make sure
你这样决定不是一时冲动
that you're in it for the long haul.
唐娜  我言出必行不会反悔的
Donna, I would never go back on my word.
你以前没少反悔而且你也清楚
That's not true and you know it.
你总是喜欢冲动之下
You make impulsive decisions
做出决定然后又反悔
and you go back on them all the time.
-那不一样  -怎么不一样
- This is different. - How?
因为这事关孩子
Because it's a baby.
我不会这么对待孩子的
I would never do that to a baby.
我相信你  但我的意思是
I hear you, but all I'm saying is,
不要匆忙决定
don't do something rash.
因为这种事不是你想反悔就可以反悔的
Because this isn't something you can change your mind about.
你们逗我呢吧
You got to be kidding.
你们瞒着我去见受害人的父亲
You went to see the victim's father without telling me?
杰西卡  这件事不能等我们必须弄清楚
Jessica, we didn't have time and we had to know.
就像你教给哈维  哈维又教给我的那样
And like you taught Harvey and Harvey taught me,
事后求原谅比事前求允许要好的多
it's better to ask forgiveness than permission.
你不是要求我这些
You're not asking for either one.
你是在要求我在公开法庭
You're asking me to accuse the man
控告这个男人妨碍司法公正
of obstruction of justice in open court.
杰西卡  我们在他的眼神里看到了真相
Jessica, we looked the man in the eye,
我发誓  就是他做的
and I'm telling you, he did it.
我不在乎他有没有做过
I don't give a shit if he did it or not.
我们根本无法证明他做过
There's no way on the planet we can prove it.
只要你在出庭时戳穿他就不需要证明
We don't have to prove it if you can break him on the stand.
你是不是疯了呀
Are you out of your goddamn mind?
-这是唯一的办法  -这不是
- It's the only way-- - It's not the only way.
-我也不打算如此  -你到底在怕什么
- And I'm not doing it. - What're you so afraid of?
你居然敢对我说这句话
Don't you dare say that to me.
那个男人的命掌握在我的手里
That man's life is in my hands
而且就是因为你未婚妻告诉他不要交易
because your fiancée told him not to take the deal.
要是我们攻击受害人父亲又适得其反
And if we attack the father and it backfires,
我们会完全失去陪审团的信任而他也就完了
we lose the jury for good and his life is over.
杰西卡  这个家伙想告诉人们真相
Jessica, this guy wants to tell everyone the truth
因为他为此骄傲
because he's proud of it.
你只需要引导他说出他想说的话
You just need to lead him right where he's dying to go.
如果我做不到呢
And what if I can't do that?
迈克有个主意
Mike has something that might help.
你说的是什么
What're you talking about?
我想问你看过《义海雄风》吗
I'm asking if you've seen the movie "A Few Good Men."
唐娜  你在这做什么
Donna, what're you doing here?
等你啊
Waiting for you.
因为我给你打了电话发了短信
Because I've been calling you and texting you
很明显你就没看手机
and you obviously haven't checked your phone.
我没看手机
I haven't checked my phone
是因为我去拜访了我们的每一位客户
because I've been going to every client
向他们保证
we have reassuring them
萨特会收回他说的胡话
that Sutter's gonna recant his bullshit
并且吉姆・雷诺兹不会离开
and Jim Reynolds isn't going anywhere.
如果你不尽快采取措施
Yeah, well, if you don't do something soon,
你就得收回你刚说的话了
you're gonna have to recant that.
你到底在说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
吉姆・雷诺兹之前打来电话
Jim Reynolds called.
他们把董事会改到明天了
They moved his board meeting to tomorrow.
-我们需要谈谈  -真是难以置信
- We need to talk. - I don't believe this.
我马上要进行我人生中最重要的盘诘
I'm about to give the most important cross examination in my life
你们居然选这个时刻突然出现
and you're showing up now?
杰西卡  我们给你留了十几条留言
Jessica, we left you a dozen messages.
吉姆・雷诺兹的董事提前了董事会
Jim Reynolds' board moved up the meeting.
那就告诉他们延后因为我现在去不了
Then tell them to push it back because I can't go right now.
该死  你还不明白吗
Goddamn it, don't you get it?
他们提前开会就是为了能尽快结束
They moved it up so they can get it over with.
他们要炒掉雷诺兹还有我们
They're gonna fire Reynolds and they're fire us.
而他说的很清楚你一定要出席
And he made it clear that you need to be there.
杰西卡  路易说的没错
Jessica, Louis is right.
如果你不和我们一起出席
If we show up without you,
那我们去了也是白去
we may as well not show up at all.
辩方律师准备好发问了吗
Is the defense ready to proceed?
法官大人  我想申请半天的延期审理
Your Honor, I'd like to ask for a half-day continuance.
基于什么理由
On what grounds?
事关我律所的生死存亡
It has to do with my law firm's survival.
那就让她的同事接管半天
Then let her associate take the reins for half a day.
她还没做好这个准备
She's not ready for this.
她倒是为别的事准备的挺好
Well, she was ready for the other thing.
那并不一样  检方也很清楚
That was different and the prosecution knows it.
我知道的是你的律所发生的事
What I know is whatever's happening with your firm
不是我该管的
is not my concern.
所以要么让你的助手盘诘
So either let your associate handle this
要么你来
or handle it yourself.
但案子要照常审理
But this case is moving forward.
你们尽力办吧
Do whatever you can.
我不能为了他们的权力斗争而放弃伦纳德
I'm not abandoning Leonard to some corporate power struggle.
这不是什么权力斗争
This isn't a goddamn power struggle.
我们的公司要倒闭了
We're gonna go out of business.
我现在没空想这些  路易
I can't think about that right now, Louis.
那个男人命悬一线
That man's life is on the line,
我不能袖手旁观
and I'm not hanging him out to dry.
皮尔逊女士  你准备好开始了吗
Ms. Pearson, are you ready to proceed?
准备好了  法官大人
We are, Your Honor.
辩方律师想传唤维克多・福雷斯特出庭
Defense would like to recall Victor Forrest to the stand.
杰西卡  真让人意外
Jessica, what a surprise.
你从来没来过我的办公室
You never come to my office.
你什么时候从学校到家的
When did you get home from school?
今天早上
This morning.
我要是早知道你会过来
Oh, if I'd known you were coming--
我不想让你知道  爸爸
I didn't want you to know, Dad.
-我有大消息告诉你  -什么消息
- I have some news. - What is it?
一切还好吗
Is everything okay?
我拿到了明年去哈佛法学院的通知书
I got into Harvard Law next year.
-而且我也想要去  -什么
- And I'm going. - What?
我想成为一名律师
I'm going to be a lawyer.
那你当医生的计划呢
What happened to our plan of you becoming surgeon?
那不是我们的计划  爸爸  只是你的
That was never our plan, Dad. It was always yours.
不许这么跟我说话
Don't you speak to me like that.
我没怎么跟你说话
I'm not speaking to you like anything.
我只是在说事实
I'm telling you the truth.
你想要事实
You want the truth?
医生可以治病救人  而律师不过是
Doctors save lives and lawyers are nothing but
渴望权力的底层
power-hungry bottom-feeders.
律师不一定就如此  而且我绝不会如此
They don't have to be and I'm not going to be.
-我教给你的东西更好  -不  爸爸
- And I raised you better. - No, Dad.
你教我做能激励我的事
You raised me to do what inspires me.
而能激励我的事情  就是做名律师
And what inspires me is to be a lawyer.
你去那所学校
You go to that school,
就会染上他们的律师思维
you're gonna get infected with their lawyer mind-set
等你出来
and when you come out,
就会不在乎自己的同胞
you're not gonna give a shit about your fellow man.
如果你真这么想
If you think that,
那你应该再多花点时间跟我相处
then you should've spent more time with me.
因为你一点都不了解我
Because you don't know me at all.
皮尔逊女士
Ms. Pearson?
皮尔逊女士  你准备好了吗
Ms. Pearson, are you ready?
福雷斯特先生
Mr. Forrest...
那一晚许多人的生活都被毁掉了
so many lives were ruined that night.
你女儿的  她男友的  还有你的
Your daughter's, her boyfriend's, yours.
这是个问题吗
Is there a question?
总得有人为其付出代价  不是吗
Someone had to pay for that, didn't they?
该付出代价的人也付了
Yeah, they sure as hell did.
所以你付钱给玛利亚・戈麦斯
Is that why you paid for Maria Gomez
让她去戒毒所  致使她无法出庭
to go to rehab to keep her from testifying
为贝利先生的审判作证吗
at Mr. Bailey's trial?
-什么  -反对  法官大人
- What? - Objection, Your Honor,
她在让受害者受审
she's putting the victim on trial.
我当事人才是受害者
My client is the victim here.
皮尔逊女士  你最好尽快提出证据
Ms. Pearson, you better back this up fast.
那就让证人回答我的问题
Then ask the witness to answer my question.
我昨天之前都没听说过那女人的名字
I never even heard of that woman until yesterday.
法官大人  辩方申请提交证据
Your Honor, the defense would like to admit into evidence
是艾莉森・多布森12年前
the admissions form for an Allison Dobsen
进入路径康复中心的申请表
into the Pathways Rehabilitation Center from 12 years ago.
那是...谁
Wha--who is that?
她是玛利亚・戈麦斯的室友
She was Maria Gomez's roommate.
我会让她出庭作证
And I'm gonna put her on the stand.
不  你不能那么做
No, that's can't be. No--you can't do that.
她会作证玛利亚曾告诉她
And she's going to say that Maria told her
自己为抛弃朋友感到羞愧
that she felt terrible about abandoning her friend.
-反对  传闻证据  -不  她不会的
- Objection, hearsay. - No, she won't.
-反对无效  -她还会作证说
- Overruled. - And she's going to testify
是你付钱让玛利亚去那里的
that you paid for Maria to be there.
我什么都没有做
I had nothing to do with anything.
她可不会这么说
That's not what she's going to say.
-我不在乎  她说谎  -她为什么说谎
- I don't care, she's lying. - Why would she lie?
她只想让真相大白
She just wants to put the record straight.
-真相已经大白了  -她室友可不同意
- The record is straight. - Not according to her roommate.
-她在说谎  -反对  纠缠证人
- She's lying! - Objection, badgering.
你怎么知道的呢
How could you know?
因为玛利亚・戈麦斯就没有室友
Because Maria Gomez didn't have a roommate!
你刚刚说什么
What did you just say?
是  我给她钱了
Yes, I paid for her.
因为她是个瘾君子  只要能让他脱罪
Because she's a junkie who'd say anything
她什么话都能说  所以我把她弄走了
to get him out of what he did, so I got her out of the way
因为就是他干的
'cause he did it.
-福雷斯特先生  -就是他干的
- Mr. Forrest-- - He did it!
法官大人
Your Honor...
辩方请求判决贝利先生无罪
the defense asks that Mr. Bailey be exonerated
立即撤销他所有刑期
and his sentence be commuted immediately.
马斯登先生
Mr. Marsden?
我们没有意见  法官大人
We have no objections, Your Honor.
那么陪审团可以解散了
Then the jury may be excused.
贝利先生
And Mr. Bailey...
你自由了
you're free.
我不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我们做到了
We did it.
我真的感激不尽
I can't thank you enough.
你不用感激我  伦纳德
You don't have to thank me, Leonard.
你只需要走出那扇门
You just have to walk out that door.
真是次漂亮的盘诘
That was one hell of a cross.
我很想谦虚一下说没什么
Well, I'd like to say it was no big deal,
我一定是在说谎  如果我说这不是
but I'd be lying if I didn't say
我整个职业生涯中最满意的时刻
it was the most satisfying moment of my entire career.
这是什么
What's this?
我接到了吉姆・雷诺兹的电话
Got a call from Jim Reynolds.
她说如果你今天不到场
He said that if you didn't show today,
他们就会跟我签约
they were gonna sign with me.
我们都知道你没出现
And we both know you didn't show.
你想合并
You want to merge?
我说那些关于希望有对手的话
I said all that stuff about rivals
是因为我不想当哈维的面说这些
because I didn't want to say this in front of Harvey.
但我知道你们故意输掉萨特的案子是为了迈克
But I know you tanked the Sutter case for Mike
你为瑞秋做的事我也都看在眼里
and I can see what you've been doing for Rachel.
这不只是职业行为
So this isn't just professional.
对我来说  这是个人恩情
For me, it's personal.
-罗伯特  -杰西卡
- Robert-- - Jessica,
你面前有座山要搬
you got to knock down the mountain.
没有帮助  你没法重新站起来
Without help, you're not gonna be able get back up.
拜托你  接受我的帮助吧
Please, take my hand.
我很感谢你的提议
I appreciate your offer
比你想的还要感激  罗伯特
more than you know, Robert.
但我做首席命名合伙人太久了
But I've had my name first for too long.
不能接受我的名字列于他人之后
I can't go back to having it last.
杰西卡  你不这么做
Jessica, if you don't do this,
你的名字就哪里都不存在了
you're not gonna have it anywhere.
那就不在吧
Then so be it.
再说我们都知道  律师不过是
Besides, we both know lawyers are nothing but
渴望权力的底层
power-hungry bottom-feeders, anyway.
你俩谁都不像杰西卡・皮尔逊
You two don't look like Jessica Pearson.
不过这也不重要了
Then again, it doesn't really matter,
因为15分钟后  你们律所就不再
because in 15 minutes, your firm is no longer going to be
受雇于这家公司了
in the employ of this company.
或许是
Maybe not.
但在我们还受雇于它之时
But while we are,
我认为你需要加把椅子
I think you're gonna need one more chair.
你们在说什么
What're you talking about?
我们在说你们最新的股权人
We're talking about your brand new largest shareholder.
什么股权人
What shareholder?
各位  我是斯图・布齐尼
Hey, guy. Stu Buzzini.
这个最头上的椅子看起来挺适合我的
This one at the head of the table looks good to me.
我不管你是谁
Look, I don't care who you are
你买了多少股份
or how many shares you bought.
但你不是这个董事会的成员
You're not a member of this board.
对  但下个季度  我就是了
No, but as of next quarter, I will be.
所以要么你们留下他俩做你们的律师
So either you keep these two as your lawyers
吉姆・雷诺兹做首席执行官
and Jim Reynolds as your CEO,
要么下次会议  你就不是董事了
or at our next meeting, you'll be out on your ass.
你不能这么对我
You can't do this to me.
你错了  唐纳德
That's where you're wrong, Donald.
我们可以  而且已经做了
We can and we did.
因为他刚刚买下了你的公司
Because he just bought up your company
而你惹错了一个大人物
and you messed with the wrong goddamn Marine.
你在说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
是呀  你说什么呢
Yeah, what are you talkin' about?
-他在引用《义海雄风》  -知己啊
- He's quoting "A Few Good Men." - Finally, somebody gets me.
我支持你  兄弟
I got your back, bro.
别跟我称兄道弟  伙计
Don't bro me, dude.
-没问题  长官  -我能加入吗
- You got it, Chief. - Hey, can I get in on this?
不行
No.
我给你带了礼物
I got you a present.
你不用这样的
You didn't have to do that.
我知道
I know.
我知道我们不该在那儿拍照
I know we're not supposed to take pictures in there,
但我没忍住
but I couldn't help myself.
太不可思议了
This is unbelievable.
不
No.
你为那个人做的才叫不可思议
What you did for that man is unbelievable.
哈维给了我份工作
Harvey offered me a job.
回律所去
Back to the firm...
做顾问
as a consultant.
你打算怎么做
What are you gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
那是什么  茶吗
What is that, a cup of tea?
安静一小会儿  思考一下
Just a moment of quiet reflection.
让安静去死吧
Well, to hell with that.
这是庆祝时刻
This is a moment for celebration.
没错
That's right.
因为今天我们不仅救下一个人的命
'Cause a man's life wasn't the only thing saved today.
我猜猜
Don't tell me.
你们想办法留住了吉姆・雷诺兹
You managed to lock down Jim Reynolds after all.
是的
We did.
律所保住了  杰西卡
The firm is safe, Jessica.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
但这不再是我的律所了
But it's not my firm anymore.
是你们的
It's yours.
什么叫"我们的"
What do you mean, "Ours"?
意思是我已经决定退职了
I mean, I've decided to step down.
-什么  -杰西卡
- What? - Jessica--
这一路走过来
Listen, somewhere along the way,
我已经忘记了自己做律师的初衷
I forgot why I became a lawyer in the first place.
我不是要追求金钱和权力
And it wasn't just to fight for money and power.
而是要为更重要的事奋斗的
It was to fight for something more.
胡说  你这不是要为更重要的东西奋斗
Bullshit, you're not fighting for something more,
你是要逃跑
you're running away.
-路易  -不
- Louis-- - No.
我们累得四脚朝天才救下这家律所
We bust our ass to save this goddamn place,
她就决定放弃然后走人吗
she decides to up and leave?
我们为公司投入了心血的
We committed to this.
路易  她没有对不起你
Louis, she isn't doing this to you.
她是为了对得起自己
She's doing it for herself.
我不管她为什么
I don't give a shit why she's doing it.
这是极度自私的行为  这不能发生
It's selfish and self-serving and it's not gonna happen.
你以为我想这么做吗  路易
Do you think I want to goddamn want do this, Louis?
我别无选择
I have to do this.
我们刚把它们救回来
You can't just throw this all away
你不能就这么抛下一切
after we gave everything to save it.
够了
That's enough.
路易  在合伙人离开前
Louis, after the partners left,
我们发誓要贡献最后一点力量
we swore we were gonna dedicate every ounce of blood, sweat,
无论是血液汗水还是泪水  投入这里
and tears we had to this place.
但我们没有
But we didn't.
哈维和我一直专注于救出迈克
Harvey and I focused on getting Mike out,
杰西卡和瑞秋专注于伦纳德・贝利
Jessica and Rachel focused on Leonard Bailey,
而你则在一心寻找真爱
and you focused on finding love in your life.
-不是这样的  -就是这样的
- That's not true. - Yes it is.
我还没准备好放弃律所
I'm not ready to give up the firm.
没人说你要放弃律所  路易
No one's saying you have to give up the firm, Louis.
你只需要放我走
You just have to let me go.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
跟你说实话
Tell you the truth,
这是我人生第一次
for first time in my life,
完全充满了未知
I'm not sure about anything,
这一点真的让我怕得要死
and it scares the shit out of me.
但我确定我要这么做
But I'm sure I have to do this.
敬皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特
To Pearson Specter Litt.
你忙吗
You busy?
当然不忙
Of course not.
我知道你跟我说要花点时间思考
I know you told me to sleep on it.
但我不知道那意思是一天还是两天
I didn't know if that meant take a day, two days.
我真的没经历过这种情况
I've never really been in this position before.
-路易  对不起  -我要说的是
- Louis, I'm sorry-- - Here's the thing.
我思考了
I tried to sleep on it,
但我只能想象到没有你  和你
and all I could do was picture a life without you
还未出世的漂亮孩子的生活
and your beautiful unborn baby
只是想想以后我的生活里没有你
and it just made me crazy to think
都快要把我折磨疯了
I wouldn't be part a of it.
塔拉  你要知道我不会今天说好
But Tara, you need to know that I am not gonna say yes
明天就变卦
today and change my mind tomorrow.
我不知道在问你一个问题之前
And I don't know how to give you that reassurance
怎么给你保证
without asking you something first.
天呐  路易
Oh, my God, Louis.
塔拉・梅瑟
Tara Messer.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
愿意  路易  我愿意
Yes, Louis. I'll marry you.
杰西卡
Jessica.
你怎么来了
What're you doing here?
我想在你去芝加哥之前跟你聊聊
I wanted to talk to you before you left for Chicago.
我很高兴  但我不会不说再见就离开的
I'm glad, but I wouldn't have left without saying good-bye.
我不是来说再见的
I didn't just come here to say good-bye.
我来问你  我跟你走怎么样
I came to see what you think about me coming with you.
律所怎么办
What about the firm?
我要离开律所
I'm leaving the firm.
杰西卡  如果你要为了我放弃一切
Jessica, if you're walking away from everything for me--
不  我不单是为你
No, I'm not doing this just for you.
我是为了我自己
I'm doing this for me.
我不想再做企业律师了
I don't want to be a co-operate lawyer any more.
如果你不想让我跟你一起去芝加哥
So, if you don't want me to come to Chicago with you,
我就不去
I won't.
但我要放弃律所了
But I'm walking away
无论如何
no matter what.
那就放下跟我走
Then walk away with me.
你会好起来的对吧
You gonna be okay?
她是我的导师
She was my mentor.
但是的  我会好起来
But yeah, I'm gonna be okay.
你想单独待会儿吗
You want to be alone?
不想
No.